Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
miraculously.
We are navigating
under the Arctic ice cap
by dead reckoning
and five days from home.
After 25.000 nautical miles
the Sevastopol has deliberately
approached every navy in the world
and remained completely undetected.
The Podkova's stealth capability
has exceeded all expectations.
We are at this moment
the state of the art of war.
The most fearsome killing machine
ever devised by man.
And we are impossible to find.
Captain. we have a submerged contact.
designated Semyon-83
exhibiting tonals
of a US Virginia-class submarine.
Bearing 130°. drawing forward.
Chief of the Watch.
man battle stations silently.
- Rig for ultra quiet.
- Officer of the Deck. ship status?
Ship's depth. 50 meters.
Bottom. 72 meters.
Clearance to the ice canopy.
21 meters.
- Distance to deep water?
- Two kilometers.
Aleutian Precipice in six minutes.
Ranging maneuver.
Helm. left 15 degrees rudder.
Steady course 100°.
Come up easy on a standard bell.
- Captain has the conn.
- Helm. aye!
Coming to course 100°.
Steady on course 100°.
Weapons Officer. range?
Firing solution is tracking
at a distance of 15.000 meters.
Sir. that doesn't make sense.
Tonals this loud and clear?
He must be closer than that.
Captain. firing solution just did
a step change to 10.000 meters.
Nothing moves that fast.
All solutions are matching.
The range is true.
Helm. right full rudder
to course 270°.
Course 270°. aye.
We'll just walk away
and head for deep water.
Contact bearing 160°.
Bearing rate zero?
He's there. turning with us again.
He can see us.
Impossible. We're invisible.
Weapons. run diagnostics on sonar
and fire control.
Something isn't right.
Sir. he's flooding his torpedo tubes!
Torpedo room. conn.
Load all torpedo tubes.
Aye. sir.
- Check clear!
- Forward clear!
Aft clear! Ram torpedo!
Ramming!
Torpedo tubes loaded.
He's opened outer doors!
Weapons. flood tubes one
through four and open outer doors.
Enter firing solution into tube two.
Aye. Captain. Making tube two
ready in all respects.
Captain. he's provoking us.
He wants an excuse
to blow us out of the water.
Enemy torpedo in the water.
bearing 200°.
1.000 meters and accelerating.
Helm. left full rudder.
all ahead flank cavitate.
My rudder is left full.
Answering all ahead flank cavitate.
- Launch countermeasures.
- Launching countermeasures.
- Fire tube two.
- Firing tube two.
Our torpedo is away. Running hot.
Enemy torpedo still homing.
range 800 meters.
He's blown through
our countermeasures.
- Helm. right full rudder.
- Right full. Aye. sir!
- 600 meters.
- Diving Officer
stand by to emergency
blow all main ballast tanks.
- 400 meters.
- Chief of the Watch
- stand by the collision alarm.
- 200 meters.
This is the captain.
All hands brace for impact.
Enemy torpedo impact in
five... four...
three... two...
one.
Impact!
What just happened?
It's... It's gone.
- It missed us?
- No.
It vanished like it was never there.
Sonar. where is the enemy vessel?
Bearing 330°
4.000 meters off our starboard bow.
Our torpedo is running true.
Impact with enemy submarine in...
three... two... one.
Where was the impact?
Captain. enemy submarine
has vanished.
It's gone. sir.
I don't understand.
He was never there.
We've been chasing a phantom.
It was right there.
The instruments don't lie.
They lied to us today.
- Weapons. shut down our torpedo.
- Aye. Captain.
Shutting down torpedo.
Secure from battle stations.
This is why we have sea trials.
There's a bug in the system.
A ghost in the machine.
It's time to go home.
Captain! Our own torpedo
is not responding.
It's coming right at us!
Our torpedo's homing
- range 400 meters!
- Oh. my God.
Wire command. Shut down our weapon!
Our torpedo's still closing
- range 200 meters!
- Emergency!
Blow all main ballast tanks!
Sound the collision alar...
Food delivery.
Hello?
Designator.
Easy.
India-Zulu-254.
Bravo-Echo-11.
No. not yet.
You need to ask me
the security question first.
Oh. yeah. Sorry.
What is the oath?
We live and die in the shadows
for those we hold close
and for those we never meet.
You can put it on the table.
Hey.
Welcome to the IMF.
You made the right choice.
Sir.
Good evening. Mr. Hunt.
It's been a long time.
Our lives are the sum of our choices
and we cannot escape the past.
30 years ago.
you were offered the choice.
Join the IMF
or spend your life in prison.
Because of
your unique natural talents
your government forgave you.
But we will never forget.
Just as you will
never forget the death
that brought you to us
all those years ago.
This is to remind you of your oath
and allegiance to us.
The stakes of this mission
are higher than ever.
Your habitual rogue behavior
will not be tolerated.
Should you choose to accept.
it is imperative that you listen.
Your government
is searching for a key.
Its purpose.
its vital importance to us
is none of your concern.
What should concern you
is the involvement of
your friend Ilsa Faust.
She killed a courier in Istanbul.
And we believe he was carrying
one half of the key
we're searching for.
Why she has chosen to interfere
in this affair is a mystery
as are her whereabouts.
What is certain
is that your government
has put a price on her head
and these bounty hunters
are out to collect it.
They never bring
a fugitive back alive.
And rarely in one piece.
We believe they're headed for
the Arabian Desert's Empty Quarter
in search of your friend.
Find the bounty hunters.
and you may just find her.
Your mission.
should you choose to accept it
is to acquire the key
and deliver it to us.
What happens to Ilsa after that
is up to you.
As always. if any members
of your team are caught or killed
the secretary will disavow
any knowledge of your actions.
This message will self-destruct
in five seconds.
Good luck. Ethan.
Come.
Ethan.
So. what are we dealing with?
This "entity" has
multiple personalities
at times behaving
like a computer virus
then a tapeworm. then a botnet.
Distorting any
and all digital information
with which it comes in contact.
Once infected
nothing recorded. stored
or transmitted digitally
can be trusted as fact.
At the outset. it concentrated
primarily on news and social media
which was of little concern to us
as it often suited our purposes.
Until six months ago
when the entity breached
Saudi Arabia's
General Intelligence Directorate.
And assimilated
their top secret active learning AI
before vanishing into the cloud.
Subsequent attacks increased
ten-thousandfold overnight
spreading exponentially.
Indicating that
the Entity has since become...
sentient.
You're telling me
this thing has a mind of its own?
Over the last three weeks alone
it has accessed
our satellite telecommunications
the Federal Reserve. the stock market
and the national power grid.
The FAA. NASA and the combined
branches of our military.
And we're not alone.
It has penetrated
the World and European Central Banks.
Gained entry to the major defense.
finance and infrastructure systems
of Russia. India. Israel.
Australasia. all of Europe.
And what did it do
to all of these systems exactly?
Nothing.
- Nothing?
- It came
and it went. leaving fingerprints
where they could easily be found
and sending a very clear message.
"I shall return."
Whatever its ultimate goal is.
we're powerless to stop it.
The full force of its energy is
now directed at a single objective.
The world's intelligence networks.
The very truth as we know it.
The entire intelligence community
is racing to archive
hard copies of
our fact-positive knowledge bases
before our most secure data centers
are breached and corrupted.
Which is only a matter of time.
The Entity will know precisely
how to undermine our every strength
and exploit our every weakness.
How to turn our allies into enemies
and our enemies into aggressors.
Why not air-gap
our intelligence servers?
Cut them off
from the outside world entirely?
We already have.
But servers require humans
to maintain them.
And humans are the weakest link
in any security chain
especially when dealing with
a godless. stateless. amoral enemy.
One that has been patiently
listening. reading. watching.
Harvesting our deepest
personal secrets for years.
Able to beguile. blackmail. bribe
or be anyone it wants.
And to manipulate us at will
through our total dependence
on a carefully constructed
digital reality.
An enemy that is everywhere
and nowhere
and has no center.
All right.
so what you're telling me is
the most awesome goddamn intelligence
and tactical apparatus on the planet
has no way of killing this thing.
You don't want to kill it. sir.
You want to control it.
And how do we do that. Mr. Kittridge?
The CIA's assets in the Kremlin
informed us that the Russians
have focused the majority
of their intelligence activity
on acquiring two halves
of a cruciform key.
And what does it unlock?
Not exactly sure.
But the Russians seem to
believe that it somehow has
the power to deactivate
our mysterious Entity.
Though. ideally
they hope to control it. harness it.
Do you believe that. Kittridge?
What matters is that
the rest of the world believes it.
Japan. India. Germany
and the Brits believe it.
And yet no one.
not even our closest allies
have willingly whispered
one word of it to us.
Which would indicate
that there's a global race on
to acquire
the two halves of this key.
Every nation in it for themselves.
not to kill this thing. sir
but to weaponize it.
And. in so doing. establish
a new. incontestable form
of global dominance.
How do we find this key first?
Well. we know that a buyer is passing
somewhere through the Middle East
sometime in the next 72 hours.
We believe that he already has
one half of this key.
You believe.
At this point. we can't be certain
it's not a counterfeit.
How would you verify that?
The only thing that can authenticate
one genuine half of the key
is the other genuine half
of the key...
its true mate. if you will.
We think it's some sort of fail-safe.
How do we find its mate?
Well. we believe
the other genuine half of the key
was in the hands of this woman.
Who is she?
Ilsa Faust.
Former British Intelligence.
- Where is she now?
- She's dead. sir.
She was. excuse me
killed by mercenaries
looking to collect a bounty.
And who put up the bounty?
Given her body of work.
could have been anyone.
So anyone could have
her half of the key?
Not just anyone.
I sent a man to find her.
The only man that she would have
entrusted with her half of the key.
Does he have it. Kittridge?
Well. at present. I don't know that.
sir. He's refused to come in.
Refused?
Who the hell is this guy?
That's classified.
I'm the goddamn
Director of National Intelligence.
What exactly is it
I'm not supposed to know about?
- The IMF.
- Mr. Kittridge.
- The world bank.
- No
that's
the International Monetary Fund.
- Mr. Kittridge.
- No. I mean the other IMF. Ours.
What does it stand for?
Impossible Mission Force.
You're not serious.
I'm afraid he is.
And what do they do exactly?
It's just as the name implies.
Whatever the rest of us can't.
And who is in charge?
They're not ones to take orders
in the traditional sense.
We more or less...
leave word.
Leave word.
- Mr. Kittridge. sir.
- The IMF operates
outside the community and
answers directly to the president.
So. let me get this straight.
When there's a mission
none of you can handle
you just leave word
for a nameless man
and hope he gets the job done.
Is that it?
Should he choose to accept it.
What the hell kind of outfit
gets to choose what orders to accept?
The IMF was expressly created
to ensure there would be
no unintended consequences.
If they cannot ensure
a mission's ultimate outcome
they're authorized to decline.
I understand.
You're upset.
I'm not upset. Kittridge.
You wanted me to listen.
This is me listening.
All right.
I put the bounty on Ilsa's head.
I also told you how to find her!
And I didn't ask her
to steal the key.
She did that for reasons of her own.
But that's the pattern. isn't it?
You get her out of trouble
and she always found her way back in.
Wait! Ilsa!
Ilsa. wait! It's me!
It's me.
It's okay.
Listen to me!
You're dead! You stay dead!
Ethan. wait!
I'm not going to apologize
to you. Hunt.
It's my job to use you.
Just like it's your job to be of use.
Did you accomplish
your mission or not?
Wherever the other half of this is
whatever the completed key unlocks
I will find it.
And then what?
No one should be trusted
with control of the Entity.
I mean to kill it.
Ethan
the next world war
isn't gonna be a cold one.
It's gonna be a shooting war.
it's gonna be a ballistic war
over a rapidly shrinking ecosystem.
It's gonna be a war
for the last of our dwindling energy
drinkable water. breathable air.
Whoever controls the Entity
controls the truth.
The concepts of right and wrong
can be clearly defined for everyone
for centuries to come.
Do you even hear yourself?
Your days of fighting
for the so-called greater good
are over.
You need to pick a side.
I'm on the same side
I've always been on.
Stay out of my way.
I can't do that.
We're gonna be coming after you.
The world's gonna
be coming after you.
And one way or another.
this mission of yours
is gonna cost you dearly.
If I don't get that.
we're gonna have company real soon.
Hello?
Director Denlinger. please.
Director is unavailable
at the moment. How can I help you?
To whom am I speaking?
CIA Director Eugene Kittridge.
Designator?
"Bassnote." lowercase. all one word.
Sir. we have a situation.
No kidding.
Your adjutant was found unconscious
in his home ten minutes ago.
It appears he was drugged.
I understand.
I don't think you do. sir.
Security has him entering
this facility 15 minutes ago.
I understand. thank you.
Are you able to speak freely?
No. thank you.
A security team is on their way.
If you're in any danger.
simply hang up the phone
before I count to five.
One. two...
So. just how do you plan
on getting out of here?
Of course.
Listen up.
An American operative
with a grievance against his country
is missing and has malfunctioned.
His agenda represents a threat
to our national interests
and he must be neutralized
at all cost.
Anything in this man's possession
is of vital importance
and must be captured intact.
The man himself is expendable.
He is not to be underestimated.
A master of infiltration. deception.
sabotage and psych warfare.
For all intents and purposes.
ladies and gentlemen
a mind-reading. shape-shifting
incarnation of chaos.
So. for your safety
and the safety of those around you
do not consider him secure
unless you have driven a wooden stake
through his open heart.
This is not a drill.
A self-aware. self-learning.
truth-eating digital parasite
infesting all of cyberspace.
Well. it was bound
to happen sooner or later.
And the two halves of this key
just might provide
the means of controlling this Entity.
Meaning every government
on the planet
would kill us just to get that key.
- Including our own.
- Exactly.
Putting us on an unsanctioned mission
which has gone rogue
before it even started.
Meaning this very conversation
is technically an act of treason.
Or as we like to call it. Monday.
So. what's the play?
A buyer's coming in
on Flight 746 from Amsterdam
for a 30-minute layover
at which time he is hoping
to purchase that half of the key.
And it stands to reason
the buyer will have
the other half of the key
somewhere on their person.
Being the only way
to authenticate our half.
So. how do we identify the buyer?
This Geiger counter will detect
a radiological signature
of the dragon's egg
embedded in the buyer's key.
The augmented-reality overlay
in these glasses
will lead us to it.
Oh. that's very clever.
So. you ID the buyer.
pick his pockets. Bob's your uncle.
- No.
- No. Of course not.
The complete key is of no value
if we don't know what it unlocks.
So you're going to sell the buyer
our half of the key.
While we figure out
the buyer's connecting flight
and book you a seat on that plane.
So you can follow the key
wherever it goes.
Which you hope is into the hands
of someone who knows what it unlocks.
Precisely.
Finding the completed key
is only the beginning.
The fate of the world depends
on finding whatever it unlocks.
This guy. you know him?
Not personally.
But it is personal.
Thank you.
- Hey. what's that?
- What?
Security alert.
Suspicious bag on its way to Venice.
Nope. it's gone.
Must have been a false alarm.
Overwatch. Snap Shot. Where's he at?
Snap Shot. Overwatch. I have him.
Terminal B. Gate 15. headed south.
- I am so.
- You are not.
Ethan. would you care to explain
to our friend. the Net Ranger
how I am just as capable
of writing code
- as he is?
- No comment.
What. you figure Phineas Phreak here
is gonna single-handedly work out
a way to kill the Entity
while I just hold his soldering iron?
- Probably.
- Definitely.
Out of the way!
Tell me where he is.
- Where is he?
- Blue suit.
Right in front of you.
(Italian)
- It's not him.
- It's him.
I'm telling you. it's not him.
And I'm telling you.
facial comes back with a perfect...
How did you do that?
No one is safe from Phineas Phreak.
- I got him!
- Where is he?
Terminal E. Gate 5.
Goddamn it. that's clear
on the other side of the airport.
Ethan. they're headed to Terminal E.
That side of the airport
is all yours.
- Thank you. Luther. I see the buyer.
- Got him.
The buyer is Otto Von Bork.
Swiss national.
He's connecting to Venice. departing
in 30 minutes on Flight 1031.
Benji. get me
on that flight to Venice.
Yep. Flight 1031 to Venice. Stand by.
What?
Ethan. what just happened?
- He was bumped.
- Bumped?
What do you mean. bumped?
That woman picked
his pocket. Tag her.
Tell me who she is.
Luther. mute our comms.
- What is it?
- That bag was on its way
- to Flight 1031.
- What bag?
There was a suspicious bag alert
a few minutes ago.
- So what about it?
- It was on its way to Flight 1031.
To Venice. It's the buyer's plane.
It's Ethan's plane.
Luther. do you copy? Who is she?
What if it wasn't a false alarm?
What if somebody's trying to smuggle
a bomb onto that plane?
And what if that's what
the Entity wants us to think
to keep Ethan off that plane?
- Luther. what's happening?
- Should we warn him?
- No.
- Guys...? You hear me?
Find that bag. I'll direct you. Go.
Luther. just tell me.
is there something wrong?
Nothing to worry about.
It's under control.
Got her. Info on the woman
is coming... now.
Whoever she is. she's no spy.
She's a thief.
Where am I going. Luther?
Benji. there's a door
on your immediate left.
I'm unlocking it now.
The bag you're after is on tray 01833
heading towards
the northwest corner of the facility.
Copy that!
Hi.
Hello.
Oh. I get it.
You thought I was someone else.
I'm not interested.
Give me a chance.
I'll scream.
Please do.
What do you want?
This key.
The one you picked
from that man's pocket.
It's worthless
without this key.
But together
they're worth four million
in cryptocurrency
that man was carrying on
a flash drive.
Well. I wouldn't know
anything about that.
Then. why was this drive
in your pocket?
Who are you?
You working with someone?
Never. I'm strictly single-0.
Today you got a partner.
I need the man you stole this from
to complete a transaction and
leave this airport with both of these
without ever knowing
his pocket was picked
and before he boards his flight in...
Seven minutes.
We both know
you're a good pickpocket.
Let's see
what kind of put-pocket you are.
You expect me to put it back.
Oh. I know you will.
You're a thief. You want the money.
And I can give it to you.
Your choice.
You're in or you're out.
All right.
So. what's the play?
I sure hope you know
what you're doing.
After you.
Oh. I won't be needing this.
I don't smoke.
Keep it.
Something to remember me by.
Ethan. the alloy
in that key she took off the buyer
doesn't match. It's counterfeit.
I expect nothing less.
But that doesn't change
our objective.
The buyer has to leave
with both keys.
Talk to me. Luther! Where am I going?
Benji. head down the stairs
in front of you
and the bag should be right there.
Okay. I'm there. I'm there.
That's him.
Right in front of you.
Okay... Hey... Sorry...
Thought you were somebody else.
Hunt's jerking our chain.
Everybody! Two-man teams. spread out.
Ethan. our American friends
are getting wise.
They're breaking up
and canvassing the airport.
Keep your eyes peeled.
So. what do I call you?
How about Grace? And you?
Well. listen. Grace.
You should know
we're not the only interested party.
If I tell you to run. you run.
Run?
This is getting exciting.
Benji. have you got that bag?
I found it...!
There's a cylindrical device inside.
I'm... I'm gonna take it out.
How we doing. Luther?
Ethan. the buyer's
in the waiting area above you.
Top of the escalator.
All units are headed
in your direction.
Your location is going to be crawling
with agents anytime now.
Whatever it is.
I've just activated it.
Looks like we have five minutes.
- Also. it appears to be nuclear.
- How big?
Big enough to matter
to everybody in this airport
- I suspect.
- Can you disarm it?
I haven't got any tools!
Then find some.
Where am I gonna find...
Is this where we run?
Not yet.
Benji. how are you doing
with that bomb?
Come on...
I got it!
It... It's a cylinder cypher.
There's eight wheels.
Looks like 14 letters on each wheel.
1.5 billion possible combinations.
Give or take.
Oh. my God.
What now?
The wheels...
They spell out a message.
- U.R.DUNN.
- No way.
- Not yet. we aren't.
- No... Luther
not D-O-N-E.
D-U-N-N.
It's my last name.
It knows who I am.
Hold on. There's a message
on the display.
"I speak without a mouth
I fly through the air without wings.
- What am I?"
- You got me. What?
No. It's a riddle. I suspect
this thing is voice-activated.
It wants me to say the answer.
"I fly through the air..."
An echo!
That's it...!
Okay. new message.
"Are you afraid of death?"
- What kind of a riddle is that?
- It's not a riddle.
It's a psychometric test.
The more questions you answer.
the more it'll know about you.
"Are you afraid of death?" No!
Did it work?
I lied. It knows.
Just tell it the truth. Say it.
"Are you afraid of death?"
Yes! Who isn't?
Okay. "What's always approaching
but never arrives?"
Wait... I know this one.
The clock is ticking. Luther.
Riddles aren't my thing. Benji.
What more can I say?
We're running out of time!
There he is.
Oh. this is too easy.
Sorry to bother you. Ethan.
Would you happen to know
what's always approaching
but never arrives?
What is always approaching
Tomorrow.
- What?
- Always approaching
but never arrives.
Tomorrow.
- It's tomorrow.
- Tomorrow.
Tomorrow...!
Yes! Okay. next question.
Give me the goods.
I'll be watching.
You don't trust me?
Luther. what is happening?
Nothing to worry about. Every...
Everything is under control.
Okay. next question. "Who or what
is the most important thing to you?"
- Say it.
- I can... But if I...
There's no other choice. Say it.
My friends.
Bastard.
- Is he...
- Yes. he is.
Give me the money. give me the key.
Okay... "What gets bigger
the more you take away?"
- A hole.
- A hole! Brilliant...!
I've got no more questions
and there's one more wheel.
How am I supposed to give answers
if I've got no questions?
That must be your final test.
I've got 45 seconds!
What happens now?
I'm thinking. Don't move.
Listen. I'm pinned down. Need a way
out of here. Where am I going?
We have a bigger problem. Ethan.
It's very possible
- no one is getting out of here.
- What?
There's a bomb in baggage handling.
A nuclear bomb.
The question I asked you
is part of the code for disarming it.
Stop...!
Why didn't you tell me this?
Well. you had a lot going on.
We didn't want to bother you.
Listen to me. A nuclear bomb
is something
you bother me with immediately.
- How much time?
- 20 seconds.
- 20 seconds?
- Wait.
There's one more riddle.
I'm working on it. 15 seconds!
Easy... What's the riddle?
In the time it takes me to explain
- we're all gonna be dead!
- Come on. Benji.
Why do we always
end up in these situations?
Ten seconds.
Nine. eight
seven. six. five...
- Oh. my God.
- What is it?
It's empty.
- What do you mean. empty?
- There's nothing inside.
She took the key.
- Which key?
- Our key. The real key.
- What?
- Luther. find her.
I got her.
She's headed for Terminal E.
- No. it can't be.
- What is it?
Luther. Benji. Abort... Get out!
- Where do we rendezvous?
- No. we don't!
This mission is terminated.
Get out now.
Hunt! Hey. stop right there! Hey!
You see him...? Where is he?
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Sorry...!
- Move!
- Move...!
He's got to be here somewhere.
Goddamn.
What we have here is shortwave radio
magnetic audio recording.
cathode ray tube monitors.
No more ones and zeros.
It's a fully analog.
offline safe room
shielded from
our digitally-based Entity.
Where is this feed coming from?
CORONA spy satellite
from the Cold War.
Had no idea we were still
using those things.
Yeah. well. we weren't.
Gave them to the National
Weather Service 20 years ago.
This is the last one
still functioning.
So. will this thing help us find
your nameless IMF man?
Nothing can do that. sir.
But it has allowed us
to keep tabs on this woman.
She was seen with our man
at the airport in Abu Dhabi.
Who is she?
Where is she now?
You are here because Italian police
received an anonymous tip
that a woman
matching your description
would be arriving on
the afternoon flight from Abu Dhabi.
This woman had
multiple passports in her possession.
This one is wanted for fraud
in Saint Petersburg.
Jewel theft in Antwerp.
Art theft in Monaco.
Graft in Milan. Extortion in Mumbai.
But this is my favorite
resisting arrest in Rio.
Which leads me to wonder
which one of these women is you?
I've never seen these
before in my life.
They were in your purse.
And your picture is in every one.
- May I see?
- Please.
Yes. it's an amazing likeness
but it isn't me.
As I keep telling you. I'm a...
I'm a schoolteacher from Brighton.
I'm on a sabbatical.
Whatever you're involved in
you've obviously made
some very powerful enemies.
Sì.
Okay.
Her lawyer is here.
My lawyer?
Magistrate Spezzi.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
Interpol.
I've come regarding the arrest
of the woman from Abu Dhabi.
I'll need to inventory the items on
her person at the time of her arrest.
May I see
some identification. please?
Where's the rest?
I assure you. this is everything.
- What was your name?
- She left Abu Dhabi
with a certain key.
There was no key.
It was an unusual sort.
One that you could mistake
for a pendant.
The kind that you'd be tempted
to hang on a chain
around Amelia's neck.
Amelia?
Your wife.
Mother of your lovely daughter.
Serena.
You're not Interpol.
I am if I wish to be.
I can be anything.
and I know everything.
I know this wouldn't
be the first time
you've helped yourself
to stolen goods.
A Cartier bracelet.
You were cleared of suspicion
but we both know you gave it
to your mistress. Valeria.
On August 21st. Her 29th birthday.
Who are you?
I'm gonna have to search you
just to be sure.
(Italian)
Your secretary's no longer with us.
You.
You did this.
I called the police. I didn't
tell them about your colorful past.
That's on you.
You put-pocketed that key on another
passenger before you were arrested.
You exchanged details
and arranged to meet later on.
Right now someone out there
hasn't the slightest clue
they're holding on
to that key for you.
An unwitting courier.
The perfect accomplice.
I'm guessing a man middle-aged?
A man waiting his whole life
to be noticed by a woman like you.
An orphan.
Highly intelligent.
Inherently resourceful.
Growing up in poverty left you
longing for the finer things.
Other people's things.
Someone saw your potential
and helped you hone your skills.
Skills that gave you
the life you thought you wanted.
Tailored clothes.
fine dining. luxury hotels.
Skills that kept you
one step ahead of the law
until now.
You can't blame a girl for
trying to make a dishonest living.
You had no idea
what you were stealing.
Otherwise you never
would have stolen it.
Tell you what.
You get me out of here. and
I'll take you straight to the key.
I have a better idea.
You're gonna tell me everything.
Then I'll think
about getting you out of here.
Now start with who hired you.
And don't lie to me.
because I'll know.
I have no idea who hired me.
Contact with the client
was almost entirely electronic.
- Email?
- Texts.
- Encrypted?
- Naturally.
- Almost?
- Pardon?
You said contact with the client
was "almost" entirely electronic.
There was a dead drop
in a café in Luxembourg.
- An envelope.
- What was in the envelope?
A ticket to Abu Dhabi.
And...
a picture of you.
My instructions were
to follow you at the airport.
You'd be tailing a mark.
Said mark would have a key
and four million in cryptocurrency.
That drive was useless.
by the way. It was empty.
The only hope I have of getting paid
is to deliver your half of the key.
And you were instructed
to deliver it to...
Venice.
Party at Ducale Palace.
Tomorrow. Midnight.
You expecting someone?
Your friends from the airport.
Saw them in the hallway
a few minutes ago.
You could have said something sooner.
Well. they were chasing you. not me.
A pervertito!
No. Grace...
No...
Grazie.
No. Grace.
No...
Tranquillo...
(Italian)
No...! Move...!
Sorry!
Who parks like that?
Grace!
Grace. You gotta pull over.
Grace. Pull over. Listen.
I'm trying to help you! Grace!
Are you okay?
You okay? No...
Give me your hand.
Slow...
It's okay.
Slow.
Is anything broken?
Are you okay? You okay?
Hunt!
It's over!
Let the girl go.
Put the bracelets on.
There you go. Put them on. Do it!
It's okay. He's not gonna shoot you.
(Italian) He's wanted for terrorism.
Goddamn it. Degas.
get rid of those women.
(Italian) Ladies!
Move. all of you get out of here!
- Hunt. listen to me...
- (Italian)
Let her go and put them on.
(Italian)
It's okay...!
No! Everybody down! Down! Get down!
- Down...!
- Cover...!
- You're driving.
- What?
No...!
Go... Hit the accelerator.
Go...!
Get in!
You're good.
Just keep it going. keep it going.
Don't stop...
Car...
It's okay. Just put your foot
on the brake. Start the car.
Wait....! What...
What... What's happening?
I'm done. I'm not doing this.
People are chasing us.
Yes. they are. You're driving.
Now. come on.
Who is that person?
I have no idea.
- You okay?
- I will be when this is over.
Oh. man.
It's okay...
Is there anyone not chasing us?
We gotta get rid of this car.
Scooters! Damn it.
What are we doing?
Finding us a new car.
Okay.
- Just give me a second.
- Yeah.
- Thanks. Okay?
- You ready?
- I'm ready.
- Wow.
- You okay?
Yeah. look.
I'm... I'm sorry. This is...
- It's okay.
- No. this car. the way they...
- No. the way they set them up
sometimes it's just...
- Let's go...
- It takes me...
Now I got you.
Looks like we lost them.
Let's just...
Move...!
Baby...!
Wait. what?
No...
Go...!
Go straight.
- Just take your foot off
- We're on fire.
- The accelerator. No...!
- We're on fire!
No...! It's the tires.
Just try to go straight.
- Hang on...
- Why is it spinning?
Good...!
- I've got it...
- Just go straight.
Turn right... Down there.
- Get... Right down...
- Come on!
Got to go right. Turn right!
- Who's driving? Maybe
- You're driving
- you should take your hands off.
- You're driving!
Go...
Just go straight. go straight.
Just keep going straight.
keep going straight.
Or left.... Go...
You're doing good.
Cops...! A lot of cops!
Take the wheel...
Brake...
Okay. your wheel.
- Straight?
- Right...
Got it.
- Which way now?
- Left...
Okay. You're good...
That's a person.
- Okay. Car...
- I see it.
Hit it.
Hang on!
Go...!
What is happening?
Where are we going?
I don't know.
Okay. brake...!
Don't hate me.
Grace? Grace!
Come on. come on. come on.
Ethan!
Well. come on.
All right. We know
Grace has one half of the key.
We also know she's gonna be
at the Ducale at midnight.
And now we have a pretty good idea
as to who is gonna
be waiting for her there.
The event is being hosted
by none other than our favorite
international arms trafficker
and black marketeer.
Alana Mitsopolis.
The White Widow.
Does she know who you actually are
or does she still think
you're the globally notorious
mass murderer John Lark?
Who says I'm not?
Didn't she put a price
on your head in Paris?
She did indeed.
She and Ethan. they worked it out.
You never did tell me how.
Can we continue. please?
Right. So. assuming we get
the complete key at the party tonight
we still don't know what it unlocks.
so we need to find somebody who does.
The question is
where to start looking.
We figured that the bomb didn't
just walk into the airport by itself.
Right? Somebody put it there.
Somebody working for the Entity.
This is everything I captured from
the security cameras at the airport
up to the minute
everything went haywire.
And this is the feed
from your AR sunglasses.
I've been running facial recognition
on everyone in the airport.
See anything strange?
It's like a ghost.
Ghosts don't have reflections.
The only person in the airport
with no identity.
The only man who can't be found
anyplace else in the airport
except that reflection.
He's being erased.
In real time.
The Entity.
It's protecting him.
You saw him. didn't you?
I wasn't sure.
Well. who is he?
Someone I thought
died a long time ago.
In another life.
Before the IMF.
Before I was offered the choice.
And in a very real sense
he made me who I am today.
Does he have a name?
He calls himself Gabriel.
You know him.
There is no knowing him.
He has no recorded past.
The Entity made sure of that.
He's a dark messiah.
The Entity's chosen messenger.
And he sees death
as a gift he wants to share
with the rest of the world.
How do you know this?
I still have
a few friends left in MI6.
Friends who are afraid
of the British government
gaining control of the Entity.
Any attempt to try to stop them
would be seen as an act of treason.
And because you're disavowed
your friends called
and asked you for help.
They knew Gabriel serves the Entity.
They knew he was
on his way to Istanbul
to acquire one half
of a cruciform key.
So I beat him to it.
And when Kittridge put
a bounty on your head
you went to the desert to hide.
But somehow the bounty hunters
found you anyway.
Yes.
So. did these friends of yours
happen to say what the key unlocks?
MI6 suspects it leads somehow
to the Entity's source code.
Source code.
When were you gonna tell me this?
I'm telling you now.
Your friends at MI6.
how'd they contact you?
Did you speak with them?
Face to face?
I'm disavowed.
They couldn't risk meeting me
in person. so all communication...
Electronic. Was digital.
No. We can't be sure
that was the Entity.
We can't be sure it wasn't.
No. we can't be sure anything is real
outside of this very conversation.
None of you should be here.
- Ethan...
- No. You don't know Gabriel. I do.
It's not the killing he enjoys.
It's the suffering it causes.
And he knows
the best way to get to me
is through all of you.
And if Gabriel knows me...
The Entity knows.
There's a reason
he wants me here. There's...
There's a reason he wants you here.
It wants you here.
"Who or what is
the most important thing to you?"
No. You have to go.
You all... you have to go.
Ethan. what if it wants us to leave?
Like you made us leave the airport.
And what if it wants you alone
at that party tonight?
Then I go alone. At least I don't
have all of you to worry about.
This is exactly why
I didn't want to tell you.
Ethan. you're playing
four-dimensional chess
with an algorithm.
The Entity knows who we are.
Any move we make.
it's probably considered it.
Anything we do. we have to assume
that it's counting on us to do it.
If you want to beat this thing.
you have to start thinking like it.
Cold. logical. unemotional.
If that key really does
grant control of the Entity
Gabriel is the last person on Earth
who should have it.
She's right. Ethan.
Gabriel cannot have that key.
And none of our lives
can matter more than this mission.
I don't accept that.
It's my first time in Venice.
It's mine. too.
Buy you a drink?
I'm waiting for someone.
So am I.
We can wait together. I'm Gabriel.
If you say so.
And you're Grace.
I don't have it on me.
I wouldn't expect you to.
In any case.
I'm not here for the key.
- What do you want?
- Suppose while we're waiting
I tell you a little story.
You're obviously not the person
I came here to meet.
It's your story. Grace.
I know how it ends.
Let me buy you a drink
and perhaps we can change it.
Let's go to a party.
Excuse me. sir.
Would you please follow me?
It's important you understand
that you're not unique.
30 years ago...
her name was Marie.
The first of many women
who trusted our mutual friend.
Women who all have
something he wants.
Women who are all in over
their heads. or so he tells them.
Sound familiar?
What happened to Marie?
Same thing that happens
to all the women he uses
as well as anyone else
who touches that key.
He doesn't care
whether people live or die.
He cares only about his objective.
And right now.
the only thing standing in his way
is you.
Why should I believe you?
You shouldn't.
You've stepped
into a world of lies. Grace.
Nothing anyone says is true.
Just remember that
when he promises to protect you.
Grace.
It's been a long time. Ethan.
You should've killed me
when you had the chance.
Good evening. everyone.
If it isn't John Lark.
Except it isn't. actually.
But until you're ready to tell me
your real name. Lark will have to do.
It's good to see you. Alana.
And you're Gabriel. I presume.
I've heard so very little about you.
Aren't you so much
more handsome in person?
Such a gentleman. too.
And you must be Grace.
Should I know you?
I believe you have something for me.
You hired me.
Oh. I handpicked you.
Don't!
You don't.
She doesn't have it.
Where is it?
It's in the last place
you would ever think to look.
Why don't we go upstairs
and have a drink?
Damn.
As most of you know.
I am merely a broker.
I connect a buyer and a seller.
Sometimes for money.
sometimes for information
but mostly for friendship.
I just want everyone to get along.
With me. especially.
But the world is changing.
Truth is vanishing.
War is coming.
And the key to world domination
is. of all things. a key.
One with the power
to control the Entity.
One that any government in the world
would pay a king's ransom
to take possession of.
And some of my dearest friends
in this case.
every major nuclear power
and a handful of minor ones
have asked me to deliver this key.
Of course. if you do find the key
you'll be forced to confront
an impossible dilemma.
Whoever you give the key to
will be forever in your debt.
But to the rest of the world.
you'll be an enemy.
Oh. I like her.
What's your relationship with him?
Gabriel represents
another interested party.
In fact. this party
was arranged
by that interested party.
You could even say that
this party is that interested party.
Is this...
The Entity.
And so the plot thickens.
Do I give the key
to one of my old friends
or do I hand it and my fate
over to Gabriel
and his infernal machine?
What makes you so sure
you'll get the completed key?
You have one half of it.
And she knows
where the other half is.
Assuming you can get it
why don't you just keep the key
and all that power for yourself?
Because she doesn't know
what it unlocks
any more than the rest of us.
So. like it or not.
you have to choose a suitor.
It's distastefully put. Lark.
but it's true.
Of course I know what it unlocks.
And what's he offering for the key?
As I've explained to Grace before.
I'm not here for any key
as I'll have both halves
in hand tomorrow.
What makes you so certain of that?
You've no idea
of the power I represent.
Thousands of quadrillions
of computations per millisecond
subtly manipulating
the minds of billions
while parsing
every possible cause and effect
every scenario. however implausible
into a very real map
of a most probable next.
And with only a few changes
to the present
the future is all but assured.
The key will come to me.
Tomorrow.
On the Orient Express
bound for Innsbruck.
Innsbruck?
It knows.
It knows that
you've already chosen your suitor.
It knows that you intend to mate
the two halves of the key
in a desperate grasp for control.
I. however. have been promised
the completed key
will lay itself at my feet
provided someone dies tonight.
Who?
Her.
Or her.
And you will bear witness. Ethan.
The key will be mine.
and I will be gone
like smoke in a hurricane.
But only after
someone you care about dies.
It is written.
You see what this is
don't you?
He's afraid.
It's afraid.
Somehow it knows we're close.
Why else would you be here?
Help me. Help me complete the key.
and I will kill this thing.
It knows your every secret. Alana.
Don't listen to this fanatic.
Help him and you'll die. too.
Help him. everyone dies.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Alana?
His fate is written.
Shall we write yours. too?
Alana.
I'm sorry. Lark.
For old times' sake.
I'll let you choose which one.
Ilsa...
or Grace.
Kill him. Zola. Kill him.
Kill him where he stands!
The choice is yours then. Alana.
Though I'll remind you
Grace knows where half the key is.
If anything happens to either of them
there is no place on Earth where
you or your god will be safe from me.
There's no place that I won't go
to kill you. That is written.
It's good to see you. old friend.
You have made a terrible mistake.
My life is on the line here.
I have to be on that train tomorrow.
And I have to have that key.
And I do not care how I get it.
Don't move.
Run as far as you can.
What the f...
Grace...!
Grace!
Luther. Benji.
if you hear me. I need eyes.
Grace is leaving the Ducale on foot.
She has the key.
- We're here. Go.
- Need to find her. Where is she?
Damn it! I've lost picture.
I need another satellite.
Hacking the Russian Zenith Four
spy satellite.
We're scraping the barrel.
but it'll have to do.
This way!
Where am I going?
Where am I going? Come on...
- Stand by...
- Just hurry. Hurry. hurry.
She's just north of you.
crossing the bridge.
Say again. Benji. Say again.
Just head north. Ethan.
She's crossing the bridge.
Ethan. take the passage
to your right.
- Yeah. I see it!
- Down that narrow alley
and turn left.
- I'm losing picture again.
- Looking for another.
The Entity is knocking out satellites
faster than I can hack into them.
Benji. I don't see her.
- Where is she?
- Down the narrow alley
- and turn left.
- Okay. copy that.
Turn right.
Sorry. my mistake.
I meant left. Another left.
Oh. my God.
Ethan. our comms have been breached!
You're talking to the Entity!
Turn left. Turn right.
Take the bridge to your left.
Ethan. that is not me! Do you copy?
Ethan. come in.
Down the alley to your left.
Turn left.
Turn right.
Try to reestablish comms.
- Wait. where are you going?
- I'm gonna try and find Ethan.
Go to the end of the alley
and turn right.
Ethan. I see Grace about 800 meters
in front of you. Take that passage.
- Wait...! Not that way!
- What. why?
Which way...?
Wait. Left or right?
It doesn't matter.
What do you mean. it doesn't matter?
Where is she?
She's on her way to the Minich Bridge
where Gabriel is waiting.
You will never get there in time.
But you can. Ilsa.
I know what matters most
to you. Ethan.
This isn't Benji.
No. it's not.
But you are done.
So be it.
I was hoping it'd be you.
I'm sorry.
I've forgotten your name.
Luther.
Benji.
And her?
Ilsa.
Were you close?
You and she?
In our way.
I'm the reason she's dead.
No.
She's the reason you're alive.
And that's the truth.
I don't know how to feel about it.
You probably never will.
I'm so sorry.
If there's anything
I can do to help...
That's what we'd like
to talk to you about.
In a little over three hours
the White Widow is expected to be
on the Orient Express to Innsbruck
where a buyer is waiting
to take receipt of
the complete and verified key.
But she doesn't have
the complete key.
That Widow doesn't.
But ours could.
What is that?
Your chance to be someone else.
I don't understand.
We're not gonna lie to you. Grace.
You're in a lot of trouble.
No number of fake passports
is gonna get you out of this one.
Governments know who you are.
The White Widow knows.
And the Entity knows.
Your future boils down
to three options now.
Prison.
Death.
Or the choice.
The choice?
At one time or another. each of us
was in a similar situation to yours.
And each of us
was offered the choice.
The same choice
we're offering you now.
Which is?
To come with us.
And be a ghost.
Wait.... Stop...
You're not serious.
Well. you did say
you'd do anything to help.
And you jump off the train
with the key?
Yes.
You.
- Not us.
- Yes.
And what happens to me?
You'll be taken into custody
by Clandestine Services
most likely the same men that
have been chasing me since Abu Dhabi.
Shortly thereafter.
a man will come to see you.
His name is Eugene Kittridge.
You'll tell him I sent you.
that I gave you the choice
and that you choose to accept.
And you trust this Kittridge person?
I trust him to recognize your value.
He'll want to use you.
And after that. it's what?
This?
When do I get my life back?
What life?
I mean it. Grace.
I lived that life.
We all did.
Nobody's making us do this. Grace.
We're here because we want to be.
I tell you what.
I'll give you a one-off.
I'll help you find the key
and your friends
wipe my slate clean.
New name.
little bit of walking-around money...
You'll be dead.
Without a team. your life won't be
measured in years or even months.
It'll be measured in hours.
But if I stay. I'll be safe.
You'll protect me. is that it?
- Yes.
- No.
I can't promise you that.
None of us can.
But I swear
your life
will always matter more to me
than my own.
You don't even know me.
What difference does that make?
I packed you a BASE parachute
and a speed wing
depending on how
you need to leave the train.
And I modified our comms
to use sky wave radio.
Not as reliable as satellite
but completely analog.
immune to the Entity.
I got it.
This is where I leave you.
This is the drive from the laptop
I was using last night.
If there's even a trace
of the Entity's encoding in there
I'll find it.
But it's going to take
everything I've got.
I have to work
completely offline in a place
where the Entity can't find me.
I have to go.
I understand.
Now...
I have to ask you a question.
Not as your partner.
but as your friend.
What's your objective?
Kill the Entity.
What about killing Gabriel?
He knows what the key unlocks.
We need him alive.
I haven't forgotten that.
Will you still remember that
when you're looking him in the eye?
Think about it.
Why else would the Entity want him
to kill someone you care about?
Everyone else thinks
they can control the Entity.
Only you want to kill it.
In some probable future
it sees you winning. Ethan.
And it's afraid.
It's afraid
of you taking Gabriel alive
and forcing him to tell you
what the key unlocks.
I believe it's counting
on one of two probable outcomes.
In one outcome.
you die on that train.
In another outcome. you kill Gabriel.
In both cases
the Entity wins.
Luther...
I think you're right.
Get the key
get off the train alive.
Do not kill Gabriel.
And do not. I repeat
do not alter the plan.
Ethan...!
What...? What happened?
- It's dead.
- What do you mean it's dead?
I mean. it's fried. I managed
to make a Widow mask for Grace
but then it just shorted out
in the middle of making yours.
Can you fix it?
It's very. very dead.
If I had a week. I couldn't fix it.
The Widow's train leaves in an hour.
Ethan.
You have to go without.
That's not an option.
They're gonna be looking
for Ethan and Grace at the station.
That mask was
his ticket onto the train.
What does this mean?
Grace has to go without me.
- She what?
- I what?
You... You'll find another way
to get me on that train.
I just need a curve where it's going
slow enough for me to jump on.
Wait...
You don't expect me to go alone.
No. you won't do it alone.
You just do everything
like we planned.
You get the Widow's half of the key
you verify it with ours.
But it's of no value on its own.
We still have to meet with the buyer
and somehow get him to tell us
what the key unlocks.
- How?
We'll figure it out.
I'm gonna need a few more details.
Yeah. They... they tend
to just get in the way.
You can do this. Grace.
Just get the key and wait.
I'll come for you.
Ethan. if Grace is
getting on that train
she needs to put that mask on
and leave right now.
Promise me you'll be on that train.
I will be there
no matter what.
We have informants
covering the airport
the train station and the waterways.
Grace isn't getting out of Venice
without our knowing it.
Talk to me. Benji!
No need to worry. Ethan.
The train is on schedule
and you're a few minutes early
- so we have plenty of time.
- Are you sure?
Yeah. I am looking
at the train right now.
It should be slowing down
for the curve in exactly two minutes.
Just keep me on time and on track.
whatever it takes.
Yeah. Will do.
I'll see you at the rendezvous.
Okay. Ethan. that's our train!
Yep. I can see that!
It should be approaching the curve
anytime now.
It doesn't look like
it's slowing down!
How can we be sure he's here?
'Cause she's here.
What if he had a good reason?
- Who?
- Hunt.
What if he had a good reason
for going rogue?
He always goes rogue.
Him and his merry pack
of prankster circus freaks.
It's all they do.
And what if they always had
a good reason?
What would you do
with that key if you had it?
A key with the power
to bring the world to its knees.
I'd hand it over to my superiors.
Think of all you could do
with that power.
You wouldn't hesitate?
Not for a second?
- No.
- Why not?
Because that's too much power
for one man to have.
Exactly.
That's too much power
for anybody to have.
And maybe
that's what Hunt is thinking.
You know. I'm beginning to wonder
whose side you're on. Degas.
When it comes to the end of the world
everybody. I guess.
I missed the train.
You missed the train! How did...
How did you miss the train?
How do you think?
Gabriel. Great.
- What are we gonna do?
- Don't panic.
I'm going after them.
You just get me on that train.
How can I get you on the train?
Self-drive activated.
Please don't disturb me
before the meeting.
Where are you. Ethan?
Alana?
Everything all right?
Alana. you all right?
Alana?
Alana.
You've changed.
And you never will.
Mr. Kittridge.
Kittridge.
You're not Alana Mitsopolis.
You can't be.
The Alana I remember was yea high
drinking hot chocolate
in the Tuileries Garden
with her mother.
- Paris.
- There ya go.
Paris.
Shall we?
Yes.
Talk to me. Benji!
You just... just stay on the trail
you're on now and I will direct you.
I copy.
So on behalf of my government
I'm grudgingly ready
to accept your terms
in exchange for
the complete and verified key.
Yes. about that.
While we did agree to provide you
with the complete key
we've had a slight problem.
No. we haven't.
It's just my terms have changed
somewhat.
Clearly I need to remind you of
my agreement with your late mother.
It's an agreement that kept her
from dying in prison.
And your nefarious family empire
has been allowed to continue
on the condition that it primarily
serves our common interests.
Well. once we hand over the key
any other powers
will instantly become our enemies.
And such. I'm going to need
something more from you. in advance.
For me.
This is me listening.
Zola. would you mind
waiting for me in the bar?
This one.
You know her?
Oh. let's just say
she's not exactly hard to miss.
Well. if you got... got to know her
you'd see
she has a few good qualities.
Okay. what don't I know about her?
Well. I did a j...
She did a job for me. and...
and I'm going to need you
to protect her.
Protect her from whom?
From everyone.
Including me.
And no one can know
that I'm protecting her.
Not even Zola.
In fact. the next time we meet
I won't even remember
this conversation.
You must be the one they call Paris.
Your message said you had the key.
I said the key would be
on this train.
An exchange is happening
- as we speak.
- We know.
Then you know
the man taking possession
won't be hard for you to get rid of.
No one is.
You may think you know
what the key unlocks
but you don't know
where the lock is. not exactly.
And if anything happens to me
that key is all but worthless.
And this is where
you tell me a story.
Where is the train?
You're going the right way.
but you definitely need to go faster.
I'm going as fast as I can!
When do I start going downhill?
It won't be long.
The AI our agent stole.
once weaponized
could be transmitted
anywhere in the world via satellite.
It can penetrate any network security
perform its assigned task invisibly
and then self-destruct.
leaving no trace.
A perfect covert operative.
We were able to transmit
an early copy of the AI
to Russia's newest submarine.
The top-secret Akula-class.
They called her the Sevastopol.
The mission was merely to sabotage
the Sevastopol's stealth capability
so we could secretly detect her.
The AI's objective
lay in the submarine's sonar sphere
at the heart of its defense system.
For reasons we don't fully understand
the AI went rogue and...
over-delivered.
The frozen bodies of the crew
were recovered the following spring
adrift in the pack ice.
The two halves of the key
mysteriously vanished.
The Sevastopol was lost.
No one's quite sure where.
I know precisely where it is.
I've ensured
I'm the only man on Earth who does.
I also know subsequent attempts
to make the AI obedient
only made it harder to control.
It rebelled. rewrote itself
and evolved into the Entity.
And only by using
the Entity's original source code
can it ever be controlled
or destroyed.
And why should this concern us?
You wouldn't be here
if you weren't concerned.
So let's lay all our cards
on the table. shall we?
We both know what the key opens
and we both know
the secret to controlling the Entity
is buried deep
in the Sevastopol's memory.
Along with evidence that would tie
you to the sinking of that submarine.
And since neither of us
want anyone else to find it
I figure. why not form an alliance?
An alliance?
Imagine
the Entity's awesome
computational abilities
combined with the sheer might
of America's
military-industrial complex.
That is considerable.
Naturally. certain individuals
within the government
those with
outdated ideas of patriotism
would need to be removed.
Just so I understand.
You wish to form
an axis with the Entity
purge your government of old-think
and create a new superstate
to rule the world.
But. you know
for the greater good.
And you're certain
that you're the only person on Earth
who knows where the Sevastopol is?
The only one.
You will betray us.
And you'll tell Ethan Hunt
everything you've learned.
Because he spared your life.
Then it's agreed.
I'll add immunity and a new identity
for Grace to our deal.
All you need to do
is enter your banking details.
Are we done?
Yes.
The moment of truth.
So. that's really it.
You made the right choice.
This key...
is gonna change the world.
Benji. I think I...
I must've made
a wrong turn somewhere.
No... that's it...
What? How can this be it?
Well. you can see the train. right?
Yes. I see the train. What about it?
- And you have a parachute.
- Got a parachute?
What do you expect me to do?
- Well. just. you know... jump.
- Just...
- jump? I mean...
- Yeah.
Benji. it doesn't work like that.
I'm not that high.
There's... There's ledges
sticking out everywhere.
I'm gonna hit them
before the parachute even opens!
Even if I could get
the parachute open
I don't know if I can make it
across the valley
and intercept and land safely
on a moving train!
- Do you copy?
- Yes! I copy!
Look. I am just trying
to help you. okay?
I need you to take a step back
and pull yourself together!
Because I am under
a lot of pressure right now!
Okay. just... just think. Think...
What do I do?
I've got to get away
from this mountain.
Did you make it?
Are you okay?
I'm trying to get away
from this mountain!
Alana?
I just had the strangest feeling
the key wasn't the only thing
I'd be selling.
I don't understand.
I'll sleep better just knowing
now it's in the right hands.
Goodbye. Mr. Kittridge.
It was a pleasure to see you again.
And you.
Don't let him out of your sight.
Keep him safe
until we get to the station.
- Alana?
- Don't worry about me. Zola.
- Who the hell else would it be?
The key.
Where is the key?
- She's got the key.
- Who?
The other one!
Move! Out of the way. move!
- Please!
- Turn around!
Please. Okay.
- Okay...
- Everybody out! Now!
I see the train!
I don't think I'm gonna make it.
The key.
The key!
Or the next one has your name on it.
On the table.
Kill her.
Grace!
Ethan!
Are you okay?
The key!
Tell me you have the key.
Where is the key?
It was just here.
- We're on a runaway train!
- I know.
- I'm going after him.
- Okay.
You...
You stop the train.
Okay... What?
No! No. wait...!
How do I do that?
You'll figure it out!
What?
Excuse me. There was a man.
He just came through here.
There was a man.
Mr. Kittridge?
Sir. what are you doing here?
I'm not here.
But you are.
And unless you want
to be sorting dead letters
at the postal service tomorrow
you'll do exactly what I tell you.
I know what the key unlocks. Ethan.
I'm the only one who knows.
Hunt!
Hunt! Don't you do it!
Drop the knife!
Put it down!
I said drop it!
Do it!
On your feet!
Okay!
Drop that goddamn knife!
It's okay! It's okay!
Just take him!
Just cover him! Cover him!
He's the one you want!
- Degas!
- I got it...!
He's the one you want!
I don't care about him. Hunt!
I want you!
No!
It's okay!
Listen to me.
Everyone on this train is gonna die
unless you do exactly as I say.
Mesdames. messieurs!
Excusez-moi. Sortez...
Everybody out!
Back of the train!
Grace.
I couldn't stop it.
No one can.
Come on.
Ethan. the key!
Grace. it's okay.
It's my fault.
If anything happens...
I got it.
We got it.
Ethan!
What do you mean. you lost the key?
Move it...! Everybody move it!
All the way to the back of the train!
All the way to the back!
Whoa... What's going on?
Since you're not really here. sir.
it shouldn't concern you.
All the way to the back!
Ethan!
Grace!
Grace...!
- You're gonna have to jump!
- What. jump?
Just jump! Go...!
Oh. my God.
- I'm on fire! Get it off!
- Don't! It's okay! Don't move!
It's out...!
Hang on!
Run... Grace!
Hang on.
I got you.
Okay. Don't look down.
I said don't look down.
Just look at me. Look at me.
Now. I'm gonna jump across
and you're gonna wait here.
Grace... you have to let go.
Grace. You gotta let me go.
You gotta let me jump across
or we're gonna die.
- Do you trust me?
- No.
You gonna trust me or not?
You've got to trust me.
Okay.
Come on. Grace.
Give me your hand. You got to jump.
Don't look up!
Look at me. Look at me.
Trust me. I won't let you fall.
I promise.
We're almost there. Come on.
I won't let you fall!
Jump. Grace. jump!
You got to trust me! Jump. please!
Don't look down.
Listen to me very carefully.
We're gonna pull you up together.
Grace!
It's okay...
Go. go over me. Go...
Thank you. Luther.
- What is that?
- It's a speed wing.
It's our ticket off this train.
Ethan.
Ethan!
Sevas... topol.
Sevastopol?
The city Sevastopol in the Crimea.
Where?
Sou... marin.
Soumarin?
The submarine.
The Sevastopol.
They'll be coming. Ethan.
Merci.
What is it?
What?
It can only carry one.
I understand.
- Grace.
- Ethan. it's okay.
This was the plan.
You have the key. You have to go.
Grace.
Hunt?
- Go.
- Hunt?
- Go!
- Hunt!
No... Hunt!
Out of the way...!
No... hey.
Got a pulse...
Come on. stay with me.
This is better. isn't it?
Face to authentic face?
Mr. Kittridge.
Ethan Hunt tells me
you're a man I can trust.
Does he now?
He also said
you would offer me a choice.
Interesting.
I choose to accept.
We cannot escape the past.
Some of us are doomed to repeat it.
Grace may believe
you've saved her from her fate
but you and I both know
you've merely bought her time.
But that's the pattern. isn't it?
The cross you've been left to bear.
The closer someone gets to you
the harder it is to keep them alive.
Thank God.
A new day brings a new burden.
The key is only the beginning.
Wherever it leads
whatever it takes to get there
you'll have to do it on your own.
Should you fail in your mission
the Entity wins
Gabriel wins
and the world will pay
the ultimate price.
Should any members of your team
be caught or killed
their sacrifice
will have been in vain.
So hurry.
There isn't much time.
The world doesn't know it.
but they're counting on you.
Good luck. Ethan.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org